Hello everybody. It's Son in Old
Cheyenne. I'd like to call the March
3rd, 2026 meeting of the finance
committee to order. Uh few housekeeping
rules. Uh if you have a cell phone, make
sure it's on vibrator or mute. Uh when
making public comment, clearly identify
yourself. Making public comment online,
use the raised hand function. and in
person approach the podium, turn on the
microphone and tell us who you are. And
that uh final reminder at the end of
this agenda, there'll be no further
business.
With that, uh clerk, can you read the
first item, please? Number 6A, renewal
applications for existing city liquor
licenses, retail, restaurant, limited
retail, resort, bar and grill licenses,
micro brewery, satellite distillery,
special malt beverage, and winery
permits filed with the city clerk's
office.
>> Madame Clerk's staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
Kylie Soden, city clerk, before you
today are the annual liquor license
renewal applications. The applications
have been reviewed by the city clerk's
office, police department, and the
Wyoming liquor division. This year, four
licences did not submit renewal
applications due to business closures.
Those businesses are Iikes Bar and
Grill, Parkway Pizza, Godfather's Pizza,
and Accomplice Beer Company. We
currently have one license parked um and
that is 1734 Partners. And uh we have
six available bar and grill licenses.
and I am happy to answer any questions
you may have.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Councilman White,
>> through you, Kylie. Um,
for the license that's parked,
how long
do we have left on that 2-year limit?
>> Mr. Chairman, through you, the date that
they have to become operational by is I
have that here. Just a moment. It is
September 23rd of this year.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> And no further comments or questions
from the committee will go out to public
comment from anyone in the room.
Any public comment online?
Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to approve.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Councilman White,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Uh, any
further comments or questions?
Ready to vote. All in favor signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> And that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation from the finance
committee to the governing body next
week will be to approve. Next item,
please. Number 12, ordinance, second
reading, repealing and replacing
ordinance number 4603,
specifying the monthly storm water
runoff management system user fee in
accordance with section 13.32.050
of the municipal code of the city of
Cheyenne, Wyoming, and providing a
revised effective date.
Before we go to our staff report, I just
want to take chairman's uh
notice to uh let our staff, the
employees at the board of public
utilities, especially the engineering
department,
uh heartfelt thanks for all the work
that you put into this over the years
and all the work sessions that was put
into it. And uh probably during this
time, we'll also get into a little bit
of the history of it. And with that, uh,
Mr. Brody, staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, John Brody, city attorney.
Uh, what you have before you is a
ordinance delaying the effective date of
the storm water fee. Um, it delays that
effective date to, I believe, March 5th
of 2027.
U, Mr. Chairman, I do believe there's a
substitute as well. Um, but I'll just
stick to the proposal that's currently
before you. Uh, just by way of
background, city of Cheyenne uh, created
its storm water program through
ordinance. Um and that that program
further required that the governing body
adopt any fee um also by ordinance. So
the the proposal you have before you is
to amend that that fee that was required
um and delays that fee um until next
year. the the rationale for the proposal
before you is that there's been some
pretty robust conversations at the state
level surrounding storm water
management, surface water mitigation,
and how to fund both capital
improvements and ongoing maintenance.
Um, so the the original intent was to
delay um u the implementation of the fee
to allow for all those conversations to
continue through the next year. And I'm
happy to answer questions,
>> comments or questions for the committee
for Mr. Brody.
Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. I mean, I
have a number of questions if I might.
Um, first of all, thank you, Mr. Brody,
for all your work on this um over the
last uh several years. I wasn't here for
that, but uh I'm I'm sure it took a lot
of your time, and I I echo the
chairman's um comments for the staff. I
mean, they've invested countless hours
in this. we've had like 20 people
working on the billing system and um Mr.
Cobb told me that um and and let me Mr.
Brody preface my comments by a personal
statement which is storm water is not a
matter of just uh idle interest to me in
1985 on
>> point of order Mr. Chairman is for
questions.
>> Yes, it is.
Uh on August 1st, 1985,
during that flood, um my house and my
two young children and a friend and my
wife and all were down in the basement
of the house. Basement flooded in about
2 minutes. Um flooded the upstairs of
our house. The woman uh across the
street from us, a woman drowned along
with her little dog. Um, so storm water
is is of direct personal interest to me.
Um, so this is a really complex issue
right now, made more complex by the
legislature and by the litigation that
we're facing. Um, and so I guess my
first question to you is is what what's
going to happen with our current
litigation that the terrible Chevrolet
has filed?
Um, you know, I given that it's ongoing
litigation, I don't want to try to sort
of predict the future, but what I can
say is um, you know, the the actions
taken by the city council could very
well affect that litigation.
>> Further comments or questions?
Councilman Wolf.
So if we repeal this fee
uh and um do you do you think that makes
litigation mood?
>> I think a very good argument can be
presented to the courtation is has mood
>> u Mr. Bro through you Mr. Chairman um is
there any benefit to continuing that
litigation?
Um, I I think you could find proponents
on both sides of the issue of moving
forward with the litigation. You could
also find detractors of moving forward
with the litigation. As you as you
noted, it's it's complex and there's
certainly um significant public health
and safety issues surrounding um this
item.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> See no more comments or questions from
the committee. will go out to the public
for a comment in the room.
>> Welcome, Mr. Leborn.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um, I'm a kind
of unusual member of the public here. I
certainly share some of the
I think you could call them feelings
that uh Mr. Wolf mentioned about uh how
important this is and how our past
experience really should be showing us
the way. And that of course 85 was a
long time ago. And since then we've had
a number of warning type incidents
particularly uh the summer of 24 where
there were multiple
uh storms that really uh just about um
really caused big damage. They just came
in a series, not all at once.
And uh I can't comment on this
substitute. It's not in my package. So,
but I think the intent here is clear to
uh proceed with all the work that we've
done, at least have it available and be
ready so that someday we could uh
implement that fee. Obviously, it isn't
right now,
but Mr. uh chairman and members of the
committee, I certainly hope that we've
got until Monday night to really sit
down and go over some of this um that
the lawsuit is
very very important and certainly
something I I need some guidance in. I
hope we can meet with the city
attorney's office and really see where
that's at.
But more than that, uh Mr. Chairman, I
think that it's really important to
understand what happened in the
legislature and how those various bills
were handled. I haven't got a report
back on that. I hear things about it,
uh, like we're going to have a interim
study, which would be an opportunity to
review it, but at the same time,
we've come down this road for a very
good reason. And I'm sure we all know
that
one of the things that really bothers me
about this and I think it should bother
all of us about this
is the
back and forth and the question of
whether the original title 16 language
was appropriated and moved to title 15
to create the fee instead of the vote of
the public. Although we did that too
but Mr. Chairman,
what's really the problem here is the
understanding of our climate.
It's raining outside.
Our winter was uh practically
non-existent.
I think that's proof on the ground of
global warming and climate change that
has tremendously affected us. And I
think we all know when we watch the
evening news about floods elsewhere and
the devastating effect that they have.
So it's my hope, Mr. chairman and
members of the committee that we could
take a look at the information being
developed out on Happy Jack Road at the
Encar facility where scientists from
around the world are studying this issue
and coming to the conclusion that
resilience in these in our community and
other communities is essential.
And so perhaps we can look at uh some
steps we can take in the period of time
before this uh comes back to us next
year. But
further discussion and back and forth
about the law
when we have something this serious and
this immediate
uh really is is nonproductive. And I
really welcome a better understanding of
what happened at the legislature. I was
there for a little bit of it, but I do
know that uh there was a lot of
discussion and what that result was. So
again, I'd sure appreciate the
opportunity to look at this substitute
and understand what's involved so that
we could act on it Monday night because
as it is, I support this action that
we're that we're taking,
but we need a lot more information
ourselves,
much less communicated to the community.
Thank you.
>> Councilman Lebourne, I wanted to ask you
a question real quick. uh since you've
been a champion of of the Croak Creek uh
drainage and also I wanted the public to
know that I had these pictures brought
in to show you of the 1985 flood and one
of them shows the Dry Creek um drainage.
That's where most of the deaths occur
occurred in 1985.
Uh if you look at that picture and you
look at what it looks like today,
uh the overgrowth of vegetation in there
is
just overgrown way way back. So we need
to do something about taking care of
that. Uh, also all the other
growth we've had in the city, especially
on the North Range Business Park, which
was completely funded in 1985 and
billions of dollars of investment that
has been put into that area. Um, I'd
like to get your comments back about
some of those uh vegetation overgrowth
we have in these drainages.
Well, that's really uh something that
needs be communicated. Maybe we didn't
communicate it all that well.
And people look at the improvements that
we made. I mean, we we Tando Park um
right across the street here, you know,
very important efforts that were made.
the 24th Street interceptor.
Um, and of course in any subdivision you
have some uh detention included there,
but it is it is the maintenance and um I
that's the key issue. It's the
continuing ability to do that is the
ability to have staff.
Um and without that um you're just going
to have that happen. And of course, our
system is aging. Um, you have to try to
take care of existing storm systems and
see what you can do about that. But, um,
I'm surprised, Mr. chairman and I I the
answer I would have is um we need to
really take it if if we're going to do
what is conceived of in this uh motion
before us, we have to take advantage of
that opportunity to really communicate
to people what we're talking about
because
we're going to do something. I'm sure of
that. and whether it includes um
some accommodation of things like the
airport and the school district
uh at the expense of the individuals at
their homes and their businesses.
You got to spread the pain. That's all
there is to it. And so, um yes, I it's
uh very frustrating. And when you get
out along the creek and and see the
trees growing in it and understand how
that uh accumulation of silt affects all
of this, it's uh
I'm disappointed that that we're have
again it's really I come back to the
same thing. This is not a matter of the
law. This is not a matter of title 16 or
title 15 or whether you have a vote of
the people or whether you invoke the
fee. It is a tremendous immediate need
that we need to uh deal with and I
welcome any suggestions anybody's got.
You know what do what do they think we
should do?
Do they understand what we are trying to
do? We just passed two uh pretty
important efforts here at uh Henderson
Ditch and over there at Dell Range by uh
between
uh Ridge and College. Important pieces
and we have made we have made a lot of
effort but without a comprehensive
program
um we're right back basically where we
began with an inadequate system that
can't be maintained. So, I appreciate
the opportunity to uh uh speak to a
little more, Mr. Chairman, but uh those
are my comments.
Thank you, Councilman Leburn. Any
further public comment?
Any public comment online?
None. Can I get a motion?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, I move to approve on
second reading.
>> Second. Been moved by Councilman Moody,
seconded by Councilman White.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, I move to amend by sub
number 12, day of February 25th, 2026.
>> Second.
>> Sub's been moved by Councilman Moody,
seconded by Councilman White. Uh
any comments or questions on the
substitute from committee?
>> I do.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you,
uh could we have Mr. Brody, explain to
the public what the substitute does,
please.
>> Looks like you're going to get someone
different.
>> Mr. Chairman, Mark Renie, 21101 O'Neal.
I get to do the staff report on this
one.
The substitute um the the motion before
you or the is to delay the
implementation of storm water fees till
the end of the next legislative session.
The amendment before you is to repeal
those fees altogether. Um if you recall
when we created the storm you storm
water utility we did it in two parts. We
created the utility itself. We created
we created a storm water division
um within the city. And then we did a
second ordinance that that created the
fees and and established how we would
assess those fees. This is essentially
what we're doing today is repealing that
second ordinance.
Council
>> Mr. Chair, if you like a little
background on this, if you recall, um
there was couple bills in the
legislature. one was both of them
required an an election um for any storm
water utility created and actually they
were they were retroactive to where even
if you had a storm water utility created
before July 1st of 2026 you had like six
months to hold an election and verify
it. Um
second bill actually um mandated a
rebate of those fees.
So or of any fees collected and actually
Laramie did have to rebate one month's
fee or has reate rebated one month's
fee. Um both bills failed when the set
when when um Senator Crum's bill failed
that was the effort on that was um put
together by wham and a lot of people
and after that and I I was part of that
effort and after that I got all sorts of
feedback from legislators
both friend and foe and even our friends
said you have to do something about your
fees if you do not we're not going to be
able to save you next time around.
Um
we will you will be faced with several
suspected punitive bills in the
legislature in regard to storm water
utilities.
Um in addition, one of the things we
argued was if we repeal, will you make
this an interim topic and help us? And
several legislators said yes, it needs
to be done. we will figure out how to
resolve this and we'll we will help you.
Um I did learn yesterday that the select
committee on water made storm water
their number one topic. So that will be
the first thing they hear when the when
the interim starts. So
um I mean Mr. Chairman, members of the
committee, I understand our needs. I
mean I've got you know our needs are
significant. We've like got 700 miles of
curb and gutter, 135 miles of storm
pipe, some of which is failing. We've
got over 4,000 inlets and catch basins.
We've got 20
um you know, lakes, we got man, I mean,
we've we've got issues. We've got 25
miles of channel to take care of.
So, I'm not saying we shouldn't do that.
what we've done in the past and I'm and
this is I mean it's poly decision on all
of our parts but what we've done in the
past is we're spending a million dollars
a year out of the fifth penny I think on
on storm water obviously we will
continue to do that and I think we need
to work hard during the interim this
year to ex explain what our needs are
and
um you know some of them aren't aren't
when I talk to them are not um
disregarding that if we're not either
they allow us to do this or they come up
with some money to help us. So I think
that's on the table, but they have to
understand where we're at. So um
>> I had a quick question. Let's see. Since
the two pieces of legislation failed,
does that leave the original
authorization that they passed in 2020
in effect?
>> It does at this point. Um
and I and I can tell you, Mr. Mr.
Chairman and and committee members when
I when I talked to them I mean I was the
discussion was all you need to repeal
Laram is repealing Cheyenne needs to do
the same thing and I said well look my
understanding is we thought we know
there's a lawsuit we know this is a
concern we thought that by delaying
until after letting it be worked on
through the summer and delaying until
after the um legislative session we
would have some direction from the
legislature as to you know what we will
be allowed to do or what we cannot do.
And to many of them that was not enough.
They said no because you're just laying
in the weeds and you're going to start
charging as soon as we're done. So if
you don't repeal we're going to make
sure that you can't even do this.
>> So So we basically have an unfunded
mandate.
>> That's the way I took it. Mr. Chairman,
I'd be happy to answer any other
questions, but that was my experience a
week ago.
Councilman White,
>> Mr. Chair, through you, Dr. Roie, thank
you for uh providing the history and for
uh the summary of what took place in the
legislature.
Is there any indication
or is it just too early to tell what if
any type of guidance
they are prepared or to to work on or
try to clarify
or um
you know uh develop any type of guidance
for communities like us who are facing
this because it is I mean you know we
represent Cheyenne and obviously that's
where our focus needs to be, but this is
this isn't just a Cheyenne issue. It's a
statewide issue. Um, so is there any
indication from what that interim
what their what their goals are to uh to
come up with some type of guidance?
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Dr. Reing, go ahead.
>> Um, to Mr. White, it is a statewide
issue. I mean obviously Cheyenne and
Laramie both thought there were enough
issues to to
um develop a storm water utility and and
start assessing fees. There are three
storm I mean this was actually part of a
wham effort because there are currently
three municipalities within the state
that do have a storm water utility and a
couple of them been there for years. Um,
so to ask them to all of a sudden I mean
that was part of our argument is that's
not fair to ask them to go back and now
have a vote since it's been in place and
functioning. But to more directly answer
Mr. White's question, no. All I was told
is this can be resolved. We can figure
this out. We will help you.
Councilman White. Um, when the
legislature in 2020 took this on, it was
right after the floods up in Yellowstone
Park County and in floods in Naomra
County.
>> Any further questions for Dr. Renie?
>> Merman Wolf.
>> Thank you. Uh, through you. Um, Dr.
Renie, thank you for your efforts and
and nothing that I'm about to say is
going to is at all a criticism of you.
Um, but I
if you were a betting man, um, what
would you bet that the legislature will
actually provide any kind of funding
mechanism that would benefit the city of
Cheyenne and our storm water program?
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Mr. Wolf knows the workings of the
legislature as well as I do.
Um I think there are some very sincere
promises made to us and I think some
people will work very hard on our
behalf.
Um with the current makeup of the
legislature you know that could change
in November but with the current makeup
at least in one house that will be
somewhat difficult.
>> Mr. Chairman a followup. Councilman
Wolf,
>> if you read today's while file, um
there's an article in there about the
town of Hudson, which has a $5.8 million
uh
bill that they have no way of paying to
make their water wastewater system
actually work. And the legislaturator's
done nothing about that. They've done
nothing for the city of Rollins. They've
done nothing for the city of Kimmer.
Storm water is unfortunately always
about way down the list on priorities.
And it it just strikes me that
we, the city, are going to get nothing
out of this legislative bargain other
than spend perhaps a lot of our time and
energy on a fruitless interim. That's
obviously a political statement, but uh
I mean do you do you realistically think
that there is any benefit to be had by
this this bargain with the legislature?
>> Dr. Minnie,
>> Mr. Chairman to Councilman Wolf,
I think by repealing this we will
generate a lot of goodwill with some of
the members and some of the important
members.
um in the legislature, some in the
House, more so in the Senate. Um
I don't want to throw that away. I think
we need to come to the table saying,
"We're willing to work with this. We
want to see what you can do for us.
These are our needs."
>> Well, Dr. Renie, you mentioned promise.
Uh one of the things that is common in
the legislature is they say a promise is
only a promise until you elect a new
legislature.
I can't tell you how many times I've
heard that
>> M Mr. Chairman having been around 27
years now and you know I can remember
when they promised they'll backfill us
for the loss of of the sales tax on food
that lasted one legislative session. So
that statement is pretty accurate.
>> Any further public comment?
Do we have any public comment online on
the substitute?
>> Mr. Chairman, if there are no more
questions for me,
>> Councilman Wolf, any further questions?
>> Uh, not for this witness. Thank you. Um,
but I would
>> wrong then not for Dr. Brenny, but uh I
would like I would like to hear from um
from uh Mr. Cobb, the city engineer, and
I'd like to hear from the chief of
staff.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman
>> engineer Cobb, you want to go first.
>> I think you come in a little late, but
we did a lot of thanks to your
department for the work you did on this.
Chairman, I I'm here for your questions,
so anything that you have. I would like
to make one statement before you do
question me.
>> Go ahead. Um, one of the things that
gets forgotten in this is all the hard
work that went behind the scenes. So,
there was a lot of people involved in
this, including a good chunk of BOPU and
Brad Brooks and his team that helped us
put this together, but there is there is
one employee that was going to be funded
directly from this. I didn't hire
anybody other than we did hire this one
person. So, we don't know what to do
with this yet. So, we have one person
that I'm reimbursing BOPU for that is
going to be directly affected by
unfunding this program. And so, I can't
speak for it, but I wanted you all aware
of that.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Um, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you, um, Mr. Cobb, great to see you.
This going to sound like a
cross-examination. It's not intended to
be. Um and you're welcome to give us a
just a narrative response. Um but um
I guess so the first observation is that
our storm water program is now in
tatters.
Uh and that's no fault of yours or the
BOPUs.
you have in everything I've seen have
worked just incredibly diligently on
that and and on the whole program and I
appreciate that. Um so let me let me
just ask a few kind of preparatory
questions and I'll I'll you'll see where
I'm going with this. Um first of all
your office is the office that's in
charge of the storm water under what is
ordinance uh 4602 is that right
>> chairman for you to council wolf. Yes
sir. Okay. And as a result of that,
you've analyzed um the the storm water
needs and uh of this city and looked and
planned uh extensively on what kinds of
projects um need to be implemented in
order to address the threats from storm
water.
>> Chairman 3, the council. Yes, sir. And
and that's all work that you and your
capacity as a city engineer and your
staff and obviously working with the
BOPU on this and the BOPU's primary role
in this is as to manage the whole
funding mechanism. Is that right
chairman through you to council? Yes.
their the billing portion to make sure
because we were we were riding along
their coattails so to speak because it
was going to go with the water bills and
then there was have to be separate
accounts for folks that don't have bills
for water. So there'd be storm only
accounts plus the accounts that made
sense that were in conjunction or
parenting and child relationship with
with the water bill.
>> I hope that makes sense. and and thank
you. And they they've been working
diligently on that. And um um but as a
result of your work, you've identified
potential projects that uh you were
hoping would get funded by the storm
water fee. Is that right?
>> Chairman to council. Yes, sir.
And in identifying those projects, they
in fact the cost of those projects in
fact form the basis on which the fee was
established. And you might explain that
a little bit if you could, Mr. Chairman.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you to council
Wolf. So, it's a two-stage process. So,
yes, the answer is yes. But basically,
since 1985, in 1988, they did a master
plan update to all our basins. Okay,
those basins then have been setting for
quite a while with that in 88 we had a
different mentality at that time it was
all about conveyance. it was getting it
through the areas without flooding. And
then of course there's been a movement,
right? We changed dynamic. Do do we we
want to make these areas more water
quality? We want to not just convey it
through. We want to slow things down,
attenuate the flow, not create another
problem downstream. So there's been a
bit of a change since 1988.
So we've only done one master plan
update of the basins, the five basins
that we have. That was Dry Creek. So
while the premise of Dry Creek is where
we started, it's the only one we've
actually updated since 1988. Each one of
those has to be funded and part of the
division creation was to then fund basin
updates to each of our basins. So then I
would have a full comprehensive project
list. Right now I've got one basin. So,
while I say I've made a I' a yes, I did
use that as a basis for an understanding
where we start with the $112 million
worth of projects we have. The issue is
I haven't even really found the real
answer to how much is really out there.
We just simply wanted to get started. We
started with Dry Creek because it's the
most populated basin we have and that
was that made sense to start there,
right? So the whole part of this to
start this whole division was then to be
able to better plan with for the rest of
the basins as well and make sense. So we
were just getting started. So this was a
start, right? Let's find out what our
problems are on all the basins. Let's
get started with the really important
projects within Dry Creek and then go
from there. So I know that I haven't
answered your question fully because I
don't have the full answer if that makes
sense.
>> Mr. went through you. Um
that's excellent. I mean that's exactly
what I need and and and you in fact have
answered my question. Um so the when you
were determining uh and I know you had a
lot of advisor on this but determining
the amount of fee I think my
recollection of my discussion with you
was that um you were trying we were
trying to reach a level of about $6
million a year to really start moving
forward on the all of these overall
projects and priorities.
Chairman you to council. Yes sir. That
was the start. Yes. Okay. So, I know we
put a million dollars into this uh
recent effort, but if we had more if if
we were to give you more money
now out of reserves,
could you do something productive with
that, say like 4 million bucks?
Chairman, threw you the council. I I I
hate to answer off the cuff because
again I think the importance of where we
started was this has to be something
that's sustainable. So pots of money
that appear while they do help and yes
sir they would help. I think the
important part of it is is it's a
sustainable effort that we this is not
it it can't just it's not static. It's
going to be organic. So we know costs go
up. We we we know changes that
modifications need to be made to a plan
that it's a growing effort. So the the
most important part of the whole
division and the creation of the
division is to be able to analyze this
on on the fly, right? We're we make
decisions and program that make to be
fiscally responsible and prudent with
taxpayers money. That is that is the
whole point of what we were trying to do
with this collection to have the
sustainable effort to move it forward in
a in a systematic way that that is
fiscally responsible.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman,
and I appreciate all of that. Um, and
and my concern is that we don't just sit
around and wait for the legislature to
act because frankly I have absolutely
zero confidence that they're going to do
anything productive for the city of
Cheyenne.
And so what that means is that we, the
city of Cheyenne, either have to start
funding these this storm water effort on
our own or we're going to have to
develop a whole revised
storm water fee schedule and and go
through all of the effort that that
entailed and then either submit it to
the voters, uh, if that's what we have
to do, or we decide as a matter of law
that we in fact have the authority to do
this, which will then probably trigger
another lawsuit. But, um, so back to my
sort of question, if if if we at least
were to start funding some of this now
out of our reserves starting in July 1
for fiscal year 27, is that something
that that um uh would be in your
judgment? I'm not asking for a final
decision on that, but would it be
beneficial?
>> Chairman through you to council. Yes.
Yes, sir. It would be beneficial.
>> Thank you very much, Mr. Cob. And thanks
for all your work. Thank you, Mr.
Chairman.
>> Engineer Cobb, we did discuss the Dry
Creek issue earlier and the 85 flood. um
the two culverts which were then just
the metal tubes coming through uh the
windmill intersection and the ridge road
intersection those culverts failed. So
now we have the concrete tunnels there.
But with the overgrowth and ve
vegetation,
if it hits those concrete
uh culverts, wouldn't it just dam up now
with what we have in there
and not even have a storm the magnitude
of the one in 85?
chairman to to answer your question
directly. one of those culverts which
not not on the ridge component but
further upstream at mountain. This is
the one that I had discussed with all of
you that even though they put those
culverts in place after the 85 flood. So
the issue now is technology even though
it is I I say hydraulics hydrarology
hasn't changed right we we we as
engineers it's been around for a while
but some of the construction practices
there's piping that's going underneath
that culvert and what that means is so
when it does flow what's going to happen
on that culvert upstream of that is when
we get a large event it's going to water
is going to want to go underneath it
it's going to float that culvert and
it's going to pull it right out of the
ground. So, as heavy as things are, even
a giant pipe like that, and in this
case, it's a steel, it's a structural
plate pipe, and if you if you look on
closely, that water is going to go
underneath. It's going to pipe
underneath it, lift the culvert up, and
the road is going to completely
disappear. So, and it'll float
downstream and then go into the ridge
culvert that you're talking about, plug
it up, and and pull it all upstream. So,
I'm more worried about some of the
structures that are upstream of ridge
and some of those other ones. And then
the channel itself when we have debris
and vegetation in them what happens is
you know we so we showed you that model
you know it just expands that flood
area. So it it because we don't have the
conveyance capacity to carry the amount
of water we need to in the middle of the
channel. So then that water the volume
doesn't change. So it's just going to
keep spreading further out. So what I
would say to you is generally speaking
what's going to happen is again more
areas are going to get flooded than what
we think are going to get flooded
because we don't have the capacity to
carry the water. Does that make sense
sir?
>> Yes. Thank you. I just want the public
to be aware.
Yes. We're ready for chief of staff. Ash
point of parlary procedure. So these are
comments related to the substitute. Is
that correct?
>> It's about the fee.
>> Chairman through you. Amber Ash, chief
of staff. Um I'm available to answer any
questions you may have.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you. Um
what's the administration's plan for
storm water for this year and fiscal
year
2027?
>> Um
chair. through you. I would I guess what
I would say at this point in time is the
administration intends to pursue a good
faith effort with the legislature and
the select water committee um to explore
the issue and determine what options or
remedies may be available to us. Um I
think as been indicated here, storm
water is not a one-time expense. It is
an ongoing expense. um things like
shrubs and trees and um you know stuff
entering our system um system failure,
those are ongoing issues. Um they're the
same issues we face in any
infrastructure system. Um the same would
be true of of roads, bridges, sidewalks,
all of that. Over time it deteriorates
and and falls down, right? Um that's
just part of the process. And so as part
of this, I would say that um the
administration will go through um in
good faith um and do our very best to
participate, be part of those
discussions um and just see what options
might be available to us.
>> Mr. chairman through you. Um would you
support uh using some of our reserves to
actually get uh storm water projects
started um in this year?
>> Um Mr. Chairman through to Councilman
Wolf. Yes. Um you know I I certainly
think the administration
um would consider that um and think that
that it if it's important today, it's
important tomorrow, right? Um it just
becomes more important as time goes on.
Um so anything that we can do to start
addressing that is um a good place to
start.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Any further public comment?
Ready to vote on the substitute? All in
favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> No.
Uh substitute S's with Councilman Wolf
voting no. We are back on the main
motion.
Any further comment or questions?
Council Moody.
>> Okay. Thank you, Mr. Moody.
>> Uh Mr. Chair through you. Just uh just a
couple of comments. um as speaking as
somebody who
very much supported the establishment of
the uh storm water mitigation
program and fee.
Um
you know, I'm always interested in the
fact that we passed the ordinance
um well over a year ago
um establishing both mechanisms
to give uh BOPU
uh one year. It was it was estimated at
the time one year would be needed in
order to um to get all of that in line.
Uh it we then heard from BOPU that one
year wasn't enough time which is brought
us to um the original item of delaying
the implementation of the fee. But
before we passed the program in fee, we
held numerous work sessions. Um, I know
that there was a couple of work public
work sessions at the uh library on a uh
and uh there there was another work s I
think there were two work sessions done
uh before council and then you know 12
months goes by and then we start hearing
the objections and then finally uh some
litigation
and you know I was always mystified why
it took so long for those two things to
happen. When we did do our very best to
uh tell that story to uh work sessions
are already are always advertised
um posting on social media, that type of
thing. Um
my comments from uh my colleague in Ward
One are are well noted and uh you know
just I have friends that live in in
North Dakota and so after the Red River
flooded twice within the span of about
12 years uh the city of Fargo was bill
not millions billions
in debt. So much so that the uh North
Dakota state legislature then granted
them um emergency powers so that they
could uh form their a basic what's
called the metro authority metro
flooding authority which is partially
funded by the feds partially funded by
the state legislature and uh to the tune
of almost
$400 million
uh the city of Fargo. So now they had to
establish their own basic flood division
to address
uh some of the damage that was inflicted
on those floods.
We're we were trying that was that's
after the fact that happened as a result
of of what occurred. We were trying to
be proactive
so that we wouldn't have to deal with
those types of problems if, god forbid,
we ever do face another catastrophic
event uh like we did in 1985. And quite
honestly, as Councilman Leborn pointed
out, those series of storms that took
place just a few years ago.
All that said, um I am going to uh well
I do support repealing the ordinance at
this time in order to demonstrate that
we are acting in good faith as
members of the legislature has asked us
to do. Um, I hope if this passes, it
demonstrates that to them. And
seeing that we've held up our end of the
bargain, I hope they hold up theirs.
Councilman Moody. Yep.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman, through you.
Thank everybody for your public comment.
Uh, just other history, too. This was
passed before I was sworn in December.
While the big issue was the RV parking
uh ordinance that passed, I would have
voted no on it. I still say it should be
up to the voters. I understand that
voters vote against it twice. I think if
we would have given really good
information to our voters or maybe has a
flat fee, it would have passed. I looked
at that software. Some of these
industrial factories,
their monthly fee is beyond $10,000.
How in the world are we going to say
we're business friendly when it's
$10,000
or even $8,000? That's a lot. And
actually, we had a uh Mr. Chairman, a
constituent reach out to us saying there
was an error. And he was wondering, you
know, what to do. And I did tell him,
we're looking into, you know, delaying
it, but actually there may be a repeal.
And here we are. So I hopefully there
are constituents watching there from war
three, you know, and you can foyer this.
I did suggest a delay in emails saying
we should wait till June, but this
definitely I would support. You know,
we're getting questions. Why is the
legislature taking this up? It's because
our constituents have said, "Please
delay it. Please."
And then it led to a lawsuit.
I think we need to listen to our
constituents more. If we're worried
about the funding, what's up the fifth
penny, say from a million to two million
or three million dollars. I have no
problem using reserves for
infrastructure. Zero issues.
That's basic function right there. I got
zero issues. If we want to budget it
couple million dollars, $4 million for
these uh what's needed,
have at it. I think that's a great idea.
I think our constituents are very happy
with that. So, I would say this really
is driven by our constituents. They're
the ones that said no. They're the ones
that said, you know, this is going too
far. We should have vote on this. And
some of the um
you know, software, I mean, some of the
businesses were very high. I mean,
they're not going to be able to stay in
business long. Like I said, if it would
have been say $20 for everybody,
probably would have passed. So, just
know to my constituents that it came
before me. I said I was against it and
here I am making my campaign promise.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Swimwolf. Mr. Chairman, thank you
through you. Um,
it's nice to be able to agree with Mr.
Moody on something. Um I uh
the constituents will always tell us
that they want this delayed. That's the
problem with storm water is that the
public doesn't ever want to pay for it.
Uh and the industries don't want to pay
for it either. And the public
buildings, the school district, they
don't want to pay for it. Nobody wants
to pay for it.
Um, so here the city spent all this time
and energy and money developing a storm
water program,
have successful lobbyists who killed
this bill, and then we now have to
explain to the public that, oh well,
we're just going to give up. We're not
going to do storm water in the way that
we thought we were going to do it. and
which means that we're not going to do
it at all except for forking over small
amounts to do small projects.
Uh
if we're going to do another storm water
program, it's going to have to be
completely rethought
and we may in fact have to do what Mr.
Moody says which is to have an election
and
>> point of war. Uh Mr. Mr. Chairman, are
we supposed to say my colleague from
Ward One for decorum up here?
>> Yes, we are.
>> So, my colleague from Ward One, which is
me, uh, and my colleague, uh, my other
colleague. But, um, anyway, so what I
think we ought to do now is spend money,
spend
significant money making progress on
storm water.
We should not hold out any hope that the
legislature is going to do anything for
us. They will not.
Not on this issue and not for Cheyenne
ever. So, we're going to have to do this
ourselves and we're going to have to
create our own programs to accomplish
it. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> I guess we'll see. Uh, and it's kind of
like when your parents tell you to do
something and you do it and then you get
in trouble for doing it. So, ready to
vote on the main motion.
>> M, Mr. Chair, before we take the vote,
you're exactly right.
only this is the only instance I can
ever remember where a municipality is
getting their hand slapped essentially
for following the law
that was enacted.
I can't recall any other time in my 10
years or uh in just trying to be an
educated citizen living in the community
for 40 years um that this has ever
happened before. The legislature
establishes a law allowing communities
to do exactly that what we've done.
We do it and then we get reprimanded.
>> Well, I remember the other night we uh
one of us made a comment about praying
for rain. We're getting it. So, ready to
vote on the main motion? All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> All oppose. No.
>> The recommendation of the finance
committee will be to approve at the next
meeting of the governing body with
Councilman Wolf voting. No. Next item,
please.
>> Number 15, resolution directing the
deposit of proceeds from the sale of
certain real property into the city's
real property revolving fund.
>> Staff report. Treasure Lman.
>> Good afternoon. My for the record, my
name is Robin Lochman and I'm the city
treasurer. Before you is a resolution
that will direct that the $139,566.24
received on February 13th sale of a
portion of Holiday Park will be moved to
the real property revolving fund. You
may remember that this fund was created
almost 5 years ago to serve as a
mechanism to facilitate the city's
acquisition and resale of real property.
As I mentioned at that time, the
governing body will decide on a
case-byase basis if the proceeds of any
real property sales should be deposited
into this fund. The sale proceeds are
currently sitting into a clearing
account and if the funds not are not
moved by June 30th, they will be
absorbed to general fund reserves. The
governing body has two choices. You can
approve this resolution and the funds
will be moved to the real property fund
and protected for future real property
capital expenditures. or the second
choice is no action. If that happens,
the proceeds for the sale of the ne the
neighborhood facility
um excuse me, not the neighborhood, the
holiday park project will be added to
the city's general fund reserve balance
at year end. And I will stand for
questions. Thank you.
>> Comments or questions from the committee
to our treasur?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
on this.
Public comment online.
See none. Come back to the committee for
a motion.
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman White, second
by Councilman Moody. Any further
comments or questions?
>> All in favor, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed? Seeing that that motion is
unanimous, uh the recommendation from
the finance committee will be to adopt
at the next meeting of the governing
body. Next item, please. Number 16,
resolution authorizing the submission of
an America seniors foster grandparent
program application to corps on behalf
of the governing body of the city of
Cheyenne for a three-year continuation
of funding for the youth alternatives
foster grandparent program and related
support items
>> staff report. I understand uh we have
someone online for that.
>> Yes, Mr. Sure. This is Allison
Montgomery and I am the uh coordinator
for the foster grandparent program
through the office of youth
alternatives.
This three-year grant um will continue
the program for that has been running
for the last 43 years here in the city
of Cheyenne.
And those folks that work in the foster
grandparent program qualify at a 200%
poverty level. And so this gives them a
non-t taxable stipen in order to have a
little bit of extra money above their
niece social security payments.
>> Thank you for that. Uh any comments or
questions from the committee to the
representative for youth alternatives?
>> Mr. Chair Morp.
>> Mr. Chair, through you Allison, can you
just give us a thumbnail sketch on how
many participants this program has
worked with uh over the history of this
program?
>> Go ahead, ma'am.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, through you to
Councilman White. I have only been with
the program for 5 years, but I can tell
you I have seen at least 250
participants in my five years through
the program. Um, I currently have 27. I
normally run between 35 and 55 per year
of uh grandparents working
um in I have 21 schools at this point in
the city of Shinland.
Thanks, Allison. It's a great program.
Appreciate it.
>> Any further comments or questions for
the representative?
Go to public comment.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt.
>> Second. It's
>> been moved by Councilman Moody, seconded
by Councilman White. Any further
comments or questions?
>> Uh, yes, Chairman.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Uh definitely a great program. Uh
like the 250 number fits with our uh
birthday of our country and it's
definitely a good program. So I'll be an
I vote. Thank you.
>> Any further comments or questions from
the committee?
Ready to vote. All in favor signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that votes unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to adopt the next meeting of the
governing body. Next item, please.
Number 17, resolution authorizing the
Cheyenne Board of Public Utilities to
execute a grant agreement with the
Wyoming Office of Homeland Security for
federal emergency management agency
rehabilitation of high hazard potential
dams funding and to authorize the
director of the board to execute all
related documents
>> report. Welcome, Mr. Strong.
>> Yes, through you, Mr. Chair. Frank
Strong, engineering manager of the
Cheyenne Board of Public Utilities.
before use is a resolution to allow our
director to sign a funding package uh to
allow us to do a design for repairs to
the new north pro Bantassel reservoir.
Currently, the primary spillway is
undersized and a wing wall is damaged
and and is leaking. So, we do need to
make repairs. This funding allows us to
hire an engineer and get the design
process going.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for Mr. Mr. Strong,
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Councilman Wolf,
>> thank you through you. Good afternoon,
Mr. Strong. Thank you very much. Thanks
for your work on this. Um, one of the
very first things I did as a lawyer was
work on dam safety issues for the state
engineer. So, I know how important they
are. Uh, how old is this dam?
>> Yeah, 70 or 80 years. I I don't remember
the exact date of construction on it. I
apologize. Oh, through you, Mr. Chair. I
apologize. I don't know the exact date.
>> Okay. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Any further comments or questions from
the committee?
>> And we'll go out to public comment in
the room.
Councilman Lelay.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um, obviously
this is a need of our collection system
and
I'm just guessing it's a little older
than 70 or 80 years, but I sure enjoy
going up there. So considering this
expenditure for the planning, what is
the uh mechanism for the repair that
would follow
>> through you uh Mr. chair. Um, obviously
we would start exploring additional
grants. The since this is a high hazard
dam, there are funding available to us,
but first we need to have the design and
have a cost estimate before we can try
to secure additional funding.
>> Councilman White,
>> does that come from FEMA or Homeland
Security? Where where does that funding
come from? Uh,
>> through you, Mr. Chair. Yeah, same
Homeland Security, the same place we're
applying now. They have a high hazard
dam program.
>> Thank you.
Do we have any uh public comment online
get a motion?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman White, seconded
by Councilman Moody. Any further
comments or questions?
>> All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> That vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to adopt the next meeting of the
governing body. Next item, please.
>> Number 18. Resolution in support of the
Professional Rodeo Cowboy Association
PRCA and Professional Rodeo Hall of Fame
and the Museum of the American Cowboy.
>> Staff report.
>> I need something fun.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
my name is Katherine Wilkinson and I am
here to you today in front of you out of
my element um on behalf of Cheyenne
Leeds hired specifically for project
blue moon which is the relocation of the
PRCA the professional rodeo cowboy
association a once in a blue moon
opportunity. So thank you so much for
allowing me the opportunity to give you
a brief update. Um,
we really appreciate this resolution and
I have some very exciting news to share
with you on the project. So, Cheyenne
leans and the PRCA has specifically um,
entered into anou. And do I need to go
through the resolution specifically
first, Mr. Chairman?
>> So, just continue along.
>> Okay. Thank you. Like I said, I'm a
little out of my element in front of you
all. So, if I take any missteps, please
correct me. Um, so there has been anou
that has been entered in by BRCA and
Cheyenne Leads. So Cheyenne leans took
the reigns of this and they actually
approached uh the PRCA about moving to
Cheyenne. They were not looking ahead of
this time and they presented an
incredible option and they said yes,
we're interested. So that has moved
forward that has been going on since
about last May. And so um this is an
incredible opportunity for not only the
city of Cheyenne but the state of
Wyoming. This is a private public
partnership um with nonprofits. So, I
wanted to tell you a little bit of
information about the funding and how
this is going to come into being. So,
with the funding, we're expecting this
project to cost about $60 million. Um,
it costs a lot of money to pack up a lot
of these special exhibits and move. It's
not just throwing a bunch of saddles in
the back of a pickup truck and hauling
over here from Colorado Springs. So,
it's a very expensive move. Um, and
everyone is very excited about it. So,
with the funding, PRCA will spend
several million of their own money. of
course it comes. So that is something
that most people don't hear about and we
want to make sure that they know they
are committed and they are going to put
in some skin in the game. Cheyenne
Lean's board of directors has voted to
commit $15 million to this project. Uh
we have about corporate sponsorships
right now about 10 million of those on a
handshake. We do expect more of them but
I don't want to over project that's
actually money in hand. Uh we are going
to work very closely. Thank you to you
and the county commissioners for putting
forth a six penny ballot initiative to
help with the economic development
funding part of that the roads the
sewers um that will be on the ballot in
August. We are hopeful that if that is
successful uh that that will bring in
about $5 million. Cheyenne Leeds is also
going to be doing a progress and
prosperity campaign. Um, a total of five
million, but four million going
specifically to Project Blue Moon. Uh,
we have worked very closely with Senator
Lumis' office, Senator Baraso's office,
and Congresswoman Hegman's office to
find any opportunities for federal
grants as well. Um, and lastly, I'm very
excited to tell you that we have also
asked the state of Wyoming with the
legislature to commit $15 million. Um, I
am happy to say that that is actually in
the budget. It was passed by both houses
yesterday. Um, so it's very exciting.
There's there's a bill out there as
well. We had two vehicles just not
knowing which which way would um come to
fruition, but it is in the budget. The
bill has been delivered to the
governor's office and we are awaiting
his signature. Uh, we do know he is very
supportive of this project as well. Um,
and so we don't anticipate anything
going ary with that. Uh so there's $15
million by the state of Wyoming. This
funding is coming out of um projects
special tourism project special reserves
account number 446.
So this account was created by the
legislature I believe in 2020 um out of
the lodging tax and it was created
specifically to bring in tourism
development projects. PRCA is going to
be an incredible um addition to the
state of Wyoming, kind of a gateway to
the Cowboys state. So, we are very
excited about this and very excited to
use those appropriate funds that come
from the the tourism fund um to help
bring that in. So, we've got the
matching that was required um within the
budget bill specifically already met
with Cheyenne leads. Um, I I will tell
you that the city of Cheyenne coming to
the table meant a lot. That was one of
the requests of the legislature to know
that Cheyenne does want this and has
skin in the game. So, I want to thank
you for your involvement coming to the
table and, you know, putting forth this
wonderful resolution and the financial
support. Uh, Mr. Chairman, I do have a
little fact page for you if I may
approach
That's just a fact page that was put
together by Cheyenne Leans. It gives a
little bit of the economic development
um and the studies that have been done
that were paid for specifically by
Cheyenne Leans. There were two studies
that were done, a private study and a
public study. Um so just a little bit of
a snapshot of the economic development
that this is um intending um to bring to
the city of Cheyenne. And while we are
really fortunate that that it is
Cheyenne that they're looking towards,
we do believe that this is going to be
an incredible benefit to the entire
state. Uh with that, Mr. Chairman, I
thank you so much for your time and I
would be happy to stand for any
questions.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Thank you,
ma'am. Um I do remember when I reached
out to you about potential uh
resolution. If you just want to tell the
public um how that started and then how
we got to where we're at now.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Yes, I was
contacted by Councilman Moody. Um, just
very excited about the project and, you
know, the western culture and how much
this project does fit in with Cheyenne.
Um, and so we've been working on a
resolution to uh present to the PRCA
just as a a welcome and a support and
showing that the city of Cheyenne does
fully embrace that western way of life.
And so, I'm very happy to see this come
to fruition. So, thank you very much to
all of you for all of the involvement.
>> Councilman White.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Through you, Miss
Wilkinson, thank you for being here. Um,
very pleased to be a co-sponsor on this.
Can you tell us the approximate size of
this development uh in what is called
the Hitching Post District?
>> Mr. Chairman, absolutely. So the PRCA
location, the project blue moon will go
on a 35 acre chunk of land. Um there is
an additional 400 acres which will be in
the future development to be known as
the Hitching Post district. Um members
of Cheyenne Leeds have worked closely
with the Paul Smith family to be sure
that we could continue on that legacy.
Um just wanting to honor, you know,
everything that the Hitching Post stood
for. So this 400 acre development, it is
in a future kind of phase 2 and phase
three. PRCA will be the anchor
development at 35 and then the
additional 400 acres will be developed
later. Um likely a hotel, convention
center. We'll see. We'll see. Um but
that's kind of the vision of a western
development area.
Thank you.
>> Go to public comment in the room.
Any comments online?
Back to the body. Any further public or
comments or questions?
Go to a vote. All in favor, please. We
got a new motion. Mr. Chairman, I move
to adopt this motion.
>> Been moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman White.
Any further comments or questions?
Councilman Moody.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you. Um, thank you so much for the
information. Like I said, this is
something I was really excited to hear
because unfortunately that city two and
a half hours south of us kind of
abandoned their western culture. We even
see the capital estate south of us kind
of is too. There's even rumors that, you
know, is the western stock show going to
be held there. Cheyenne, we really hold
on to our western heritage. If we want
to pass this on to our children, our
grandchildren and then their children,
we need this. And that is why people
move here, especially retirees, is
because of our western culture.
And again, this is something that's
going to be great. I'm glad to see that
there's definitely a lot of unity with
this and that is why I approach it first
and glad to see everybody in the council
as a sponsor. So definitely be an I
vote. Definitely encourage my colleagues
to vote I because it's going to be
exciting because we can show that we
really do care about our western
heritage and want to keep it going for
generations. Okay. That culture that we
hold dear. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you. Any further comments or
questions?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation from the finance
committee will be to adopt the next
meeting of the governing body. Next
item, please.
>> Number 20 C. Contract modification
number one to contract number 7322
between the city of Cheyenne and
Sweetgrass Homeowners Association and
the Sweetgrass Commercial Owners
Association to outline responsibilities
for both construction and maintenance of
the Greater Cheyenne Greenway as well as
enhanced landscaping constructed within
the tracks of land owned by the city and
for areas within the public right away
within Sweet Grass first and second
filings.
>> Staff report. uh chair, members of the
committee, Jean Shrednick, Parks and
Greenway Planner. Um in uh 2021, we did
anou with the Sweetgrass Group down
south. Um they were contemplating doing
some dressed up landscape along the
public greenway there. So, we needed to
clarify who was going to maintain that.
Um, our folks at parks generally take a
mower and they mow about 5 foot width on
either side. But, um, when we ran into
what they were trying to do at
Sweetgrass, they were trying to put some
beds in and things like that, we needed
to clarify that in this maintenance
agreement. So, basically all of this uh,
what this um, amendment does is it just
um, correctly identifies one of the
entities. Things have changed over time.
um that compi comprise the sweetgrass
association.
Um we've added the sweetg grass master
association. It will also eliminate the
expiration date we had in the original
umou and provide for perpetual perpetual
terms and add a termination agreement.
Um we also added that the document will
be recorded with the Laram County clerk.
Um John Bro Broad Brody did a lot of
this negotiation with uh the Sweet Grass
attorney and um if you have any um real
detailed questions, he could probably
answer those for you.
>> Comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you. Uh thank you, ma'am. Uh
was this brought up at one of the recent
uh HOA meetings that there's going to be
a change to this?
>> Um I uh through you. Um I am not aware
of any of the HOA meetings
um with SweetGrass.
Yeah. Um the city is not party to the
HOA there.
>> Thank you,
>> Mr. Brody.
Mr. Chairman, John Brody, city attorney.
Uh through you, Councilman Moody. um the
homeowners association was involved to
the extent that they approved and um I
guess specified how the the assignment
of certain maintenance responsibilities
are going to that second organization.
If you look at the agreement the exhibit
that's appended to it um identifies that
underlying
uh that is between the um uh HOA and
then the uh third organization that is
the assenee under the proposal that's
currently in front of you. Just wanted
to add that.
>> Thank you. That was helpful.
>> Any further comments or questions from
the committee?
>> Any public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Back to the committee for a motion.
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> It's been uh moved by Councilman White,
second by Councilman
Wolf. Any further comments or questions?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body.
Madam clerk, last item
>> number 21D, consideration of bid number
E-13-26
for the lease of one new instock 40
front loader refuge collection truck for
the city of Cheyenne sanitation division
from the solid waste fund and warm
insurance proceeds.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon. Craigoy public works.
This piece of equipment that we intend
to lease from Elliot Equipment Company
is for the amount of $49,388.96.
And how that breaks down is we will
lease the piece of equipment for
$109,388.96.
20,000 of it will be for our
deductible.
Um if at the end of the term of one year
we choose we do have the option to
purchase the equipment outright for
$300,000.
This is to replace in the interm while
we have the truck that was involved in
an accident in July
until it is repaired and once it's
repaired we'll hopefully get that back
in service. Um currently right now we
have three routes and three front load
trucks. So, we've spent Saturdays fixing
them as they break down. This will help
eliminate that and give us a quality
backup. And I recommend approval. And I
stand for questions. Comments or
questions from the committee.
Seeing none, go to public comment in the
room.
Seeing none, any public comment online?
And back to the committee for a vote or
a motion.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
from Elliot Equipment Company in amount
not to exceed $49,388.96.
>> Second. It's
>> been moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous.
The recommendation of the finance
committee will be to approve at the next
meeting of the governing body. And
seeing that there's no more items on the
agenda, we are adjourned.